https://www.uta.edu/legalaffairs/notices/legal-and-privacy-notice.php

More Social Media Sites
MENUHomeClery Act Title IXContractsPolicies and ProceduresPublic Information and Records Contact UsHomeClery Act Title IXContractsPolicies and ProceduresPublic Information and Records Public InformationRecords ManagementNon-Public InformationFees for Records RequestRetention SchedulesDepartment ContactsContact Us
Office of Legal AffairsUTA Legal and Privacy Notice
UTA Legal and Privacy Notice
Purpose
The University of Texas at Arlington (UTA) is committed to ensuring the privacy and accuracy of your confidential information. This notice is provides information regarding use of UTA’s website and rights under the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).
Scope
UTA by and through its academic, research and administrative units and programs, owns, controls, operates and/or maintains websites under a number of domains (collectively, “UTA Web”). This Notice applies to all domains within the UTA Web.
Required Link
Each Web application or site must contain a link for "Legal and Privacy Notice" that links to this Notice.
Exceptions
The UTA Web consists of hundreds of Web servers. Some servers hosted by UTA may adopt different privacy statements as their specific needs require. If a UTA department has a privacy statement that is different from this statement, that policy must be approved by the Information Security Office and University Compliance Services. However, those sites cannot adopt a privacy statement that in any way supersedes federal or state regulations.
The UTA Web contains links to hundreds of external websites. The university is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the external websites we link to.
Information Gathered by UTA
UTA Web servers generate logs that may contain the following information:
Internet address (IP address) of computer being used
Web pages requested
Referring Web page
Browser used
Date and Time
Other web data collectively known as “web headers” or “http headers”
UIN (unique person identifier for NetID-based services only)
The data is used in aggregate by IT custodians to tune the Web site for its efficiency and is not ordinarily associated with specific individuals. Raw data from the Web server logs is only shared with the custodian of each Web site. Summary reports produced from the logs help Web publishers determine what Web browsers and pages are most popular. For example, if the aggregate reports show a particular Web page is very popular or used more by freshmen than by seniors, publishers might use this information to customize the content of that page and make it easier to find.
Third-party content
Some pages within the uta.edu domain may contain content that is served from external third parties. For example, a uta.edu Web site might include a graphic logo or a script from a third party.
Third party content in uta.edu is not limited to graphics, but this is the most frequent use. Examples of these third parties include social media sites like Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube, Flickr, etc. UTA does not transmit any information to these third parties as part of such requests. However, when you visit uta.edu pages that contain third party content, information such as your IP address, date, browser, and requested page are transmitted from your computer to that third party. UTA is not responsible for the privacy practices of these external third parties.
Cookies
Cookies are small pieces of data stored by the Web browser. Cookies are often used to remember information about preferences and pages you have visited. For example, when you visit some sites on the Web you might see a "Welcome Back" message. The first time you visited the site a cookie was probably set on your computer; when you return, the cookie is read again. You can configure your Web browser to refuse to accept cookies, to disable cookies, and to remove cookies from your hard drive as needed.
UTA Web servers use cookies in the centralized authentication system called NetID that utilize Shibboleth or Active Directory Federated Services (ADFS). These cookies are used so you will not have to repeatedly enter user names and passwords when you go to different parts of the Web site. You are normally required to enter a UTA NetID or email address when you request data about yourself or to ensure that you are a member of the University community. For example prospective students who want to check their admission status, or employees who want to look at their paystubs, must enter their UTA NetID so the system knows who is requesting the data. This login process uses Transport Layer Security (TLS) so the user name and password are encrypted between the Web browser and our Web server.
Some Web servers within UTA may also use cookies to retain user preference information. It is against university policy to share this information with external third parties.
Web Analytics
Some UTA websites use Web Analytics Services provided by various vendors like Google, Inc. Such vendors use cookies to collect information such as URLs, Internet domain and host names, browser software, and the date and time that the site is visited. This information is used to monitor the effectiveness of the website and to consider potential improvements to the website. The information is non-personal and is transmitted to and stored by vendors on their servers. UTA does not share any specific information about a particular user.
Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics terms of use and Google's privacy practices. To opt out of Google’s data collection, read more about the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on.
Security and Accuracy of Confidential Information
UTA does its best to ensure that the personal information it collects is accurate. Users with a UTA NetID can check and update personal information such as their address and email address on UT Share (employees and certain affiliates) or MyMav (students).
Although no computer system is 100% secure, UTA has deployed extensive security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under our control.
E-commerce
Several sites within UTA enable you to pay for products or services online with a credit card. Unless otherwise noted, these transactions are encrypted. It is university policy that confidential information you enter in the transaction is used only for the purposes described in that transaction, unless an additional use is specifically stated on that site.
Sharing of Information
UTA does not share your personal information with third parties except:
As required/permitted by law;
As necessary to protect University interests; and/or
With service providers acting on UTA’s behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the data;
As necessary to further UTA research efforts pursuant to approvals from appropriate data stewards and the IRB.
Public Forums
UTA makes some public chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups available to its users. The University does not ordinarily log public chat sessions, however, any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should therefore exercise caution when deciding to disclose your confidential information in such places. Academic chat sessions and discussion forums, such as those in Blackboard, may be logged. However, these educational records are protected from disclosure by FERPA.
Texas Public Information Act
Except for educational records governed by FERPA, all information collected from the UTA Web, including the summary server log information, emails sent to the Web site, and information collected from Web-based forms, may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act.The Texas Public Information Act, with a few exceptions, gives you the right to be informed about the information that UTA collects about you. It also gives you the right to request a copy of that information, and to have the university correct any of that information that is wrong. You may request to receive and review any of that information, or request corrections to it, by contacting the University's Public Information Officer, Office of University Compliance and Legal Affairs, 701 S. Nedderman Drive, Arlington, TX 76019-0145 (email: publicrecords@uta.edu).
Legal Notice
Notwithstanding any language to the contrary, nothing contained herein constitutes nor is intended to constitute an offer, inducement, promise, or contract of any kind. The data contained herein is for informational purposes only and is not represented to be error free. Any links to non-UTA information are provided as a courtesy. They are not intended to nor do they constitute an endorsement by UTA of the linked materials.
Copyright
Pursuant to 17 U.S.C. Sec 512(c)(2), notice of claims of copyright infringement should be directed to publicrecords@uta.edu.
Questions
If you have questions about this Notice or you believe that your personal information has been released without your consent send email to security@uta.edu.
European Union General Data Protection Regulations
The University of Texas at Arlington ("UTA") is committed to safeguarding the privacy of personal data. This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information provided to the University by prospective students, students, employee applicants, employees, alumni, and research subjects. When information is submitted to UTA, or you use the University's websites and other services, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information as described in this Privacy Notice.
1. University Use of Information
In General
UTA uses Information and Sensitive Information to conduct general demographic and statistical research to improve University programs. Sensitive Information is collected, processed and shared internally and externally, as necessary, applicable and appropriate, to identify appropriate support services or activities, provide reasonable accommodations, enforce University policies or comply with applicable laws. Finally, Information and Sensitive Information may be shared by UTA with third parties who have entered into contracts with the University to perform functions on behalf of the University, subject to the obligation of confidentiality and safeguarding from unauthorized disclosure.
Employee Applicants
UTA collects and processes Information and Sensitive Information from individuals who are applying to UTA for employment only as necessary in the exercise of the University's legitimate interests, functions and responsibilities as a public research higher education institution and employer under Texas and federal laws. UTA will use the details you provide on your application form, together with the supporting documents requested, additional details provided by any references. Information and Sensitive Information is collected from applicants and shared with internal and external parties to identify you; process your application; verify information, employment suitability and eligibility; communications with you; regulatory reporting; auditing; and other related University processes and functions.
Student Applicants and Students
UTA collects and processes Information and Sensitive Information from individuals who are applying for admission to UTA or are admitted students only as necessary in the exercise of the University's legitimate interests, functions and responsibilities as a public research higher education institution. Information is collected from students and shared with internal and external parties to register or enroll persons in the University, provide and administer housing to students, manage a student account, provide academic advising, develop and deliver education programs, track academic progress, analyze and improve education programs, recruitment, regulatory reporting, auditing, communicating, maintenance of accreditation, and other related University processes and functions.
Employees
UTA collects and processes Information and Sensitive Information from employees only as necessary in the exercise of the University's legitimate interests, functions and responsibilities as a public research higher education institution and employer under Texas and federal laws. The University will keep a record of the details employees provided on their application form, any supporting documents requested and additional details provided by any references and recorded following any interview process. We will maintain various administrative and financial records about their employment at UTA and use of the academic and non-academic facilities and services that UTA offers. Information and Sensitive Information is collected to assess suitability for a particular role or task; to support in implementing any accommodations; where relevant, to monitor, evaluate and support research and commercialization activity; to administer remuneration, payroll, pension and other standard employment functions; to administer HR-related processes, including those relating to performance/absence management, disciplinary issues and complaints/grievances; to provide access to facilities, services and staff benefits, and where appropriate to monitor use of such in accordance with University policies; for communications; to support training, health, safety, welfare and religious requirements; to compile statistics and conduct surveys and research for internal and statutory reporting purposes; to fulfil and monitor UTA responsibilities under equal access, right to work and public safety legislation; and to enable us to contact others in the event of an emergency.
Research Subjects
UTA also collects and processes Information and Sensitive Information from individuals who are research subjects in the exercise of scientific, historical research, or statistical purposes.
Retirees, Alumni, and Supporters
UTA collects and processes Information and Sensitive Information from individuals who are UTA alumni, its past, current and future supporters, whether donors, volunteers, participants in UTA membership groups, or attendees at UTA events only as necessary in the exercise of the University's legitimate interests, functions and responsibilities as a public research higher education institution under Texas and federal laws. Information and Sensitive Information is collected and shared with internal and external parties for communication purposes, surveys, providing services, solicitations, research, internal record keeping, and administrative purposes.
2. Definitions
Sensitive Information: For purposes of this Privacy Notice is defined as race, ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, health data, and sexual orientation.
Information: For purposes of this Privacy Notice is defined as any other information concerning a natural person that is created by or provided to UTA from or concerning prospective students, students, employee applicants, employees, and research subjects.
3. Third Party Use of Sensitive Information
In General
UTA may disclose your Sensitive Information and other Information as follows:
Archiving: UTA may share your Information and Sensitive Information for archiving purposes in the public interest, and for historical research, and statistical purposes.
Consent: UTA may disclose Sensitive Information and other Information if we have your consent to do so.
Emergency Circumstances: UTA may share your Information, and Sensitive Information when necessary to protect your interests and you are physically or legally incapable of providing consent.
Employment Necessity: UTA may share your Sensitive Information when necessary for administering employment or social security benefits in accordance with applicable law, subject to the imposition of appropriate safeguards to prevent further unauthorized disclosure.
Legal Obligation: UTA may share your Information and Sensitive Information when the disclosure is required or permitted by international, federal, and state laws and regulations.
Performance of a Contract: UTA may share your Information when necessary to administer a contract you have with the University.
Public Information: UTA may share your Information and Sensitive Information if you have manifestly made it public.
Service Providers: UTA uses third parties who have entered into a contract with the University to support the administration of University operations and policies. In such cases, UTA shares your Information with such third parties subject to the imposition of appropriate safeguards to prevent further unauthorized disclosure.
State and Federal Agencies: UTA may share your Information and Sensitive Information with federal and state agencies and departments, police and law enforcement agencies, and accrediting agencies.
University Affiliated Programs: UTA may share your Information with parties that are affiliated with the University for the purpose of contacting you about goods, services, academic experiences, charitable giving or experiences that may be of interest to you.
The University of Texas System: UTA may share Information and Sensitive Information with the UT System as reasonably requested and necessary to comply with Regents Rules, System Policies, System Initiatives, investigations, and inquiries.
De-Identified and Aggregate Information: UTA may use and disclose Information in de-identified or aggregate form without limitation.
Other than as set forth above, UTA will not normally publish or disclose any personal information about you to other external enquirers or organizations unless you have requested it or consented to it, or unless it is in your vital interests to do so (e.g. in an emergency situation).
4. Security
UTA implements appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your information when you transmit it to UTA and when UTA stores it on its information technology systems.
5. Cookies and Other Technology
The University's use of cookies and other data from information technology can be located above.
6. Retention and Destruction of Your Information
Your information will be retained by the University in accordance with applicable federal laws, and the applicable retention periods in the Record Retention Schedule adopted by UTA. Your information will be destroyed upon your request unless applicable law requires destruction after the expiration of an applicable retention period. The manner of destruction will be appropriate to preserve and ensure the confidentiality of your information given the level of sensitivity, value and criticality to the University.
7. Your Rights
You have the right to request access to, a copy of, rectification, restriction in the use of, or erasure of your information in accordance with all applicable laws. The erasure of your information will be subject to the retention periods of applicable federal and state law and UTA’s Record Retention Schedule. If you have provided consent to the use of your information, you have the right to withdraw consent without affecting the lawfulness of the University's use of the information prior to receipt of your request.
Students may exercise these rights by accessing their student account on MyMav using their login credentials, or by contacting the University's Registrar, Nichole Mancone Fisher, at nichole.manconefisher@uta.edu. Applicants for employment and employees may exercise these rights by contacting the Office of Human Resources at Raymond.vigil@uta.edu.
Information created in the European Union will be transferred out of the European Union to the University. If you feel the University has not complied with applicable foreign laws regulating such information, you have the right to file a complaint with the appropriate supervisory authority in the European Union.
8. Updates to This Notice
This Notice was published May 25, 2018. UTA may update or change this notice notice at any time. Your continued use of the University's website and third party applications after any such change indicates your acceptance of these changes.
Office of Legal AffairsDavis Hall, Suite 241 • 701 S. Nedderman Dr. • Arlington, TX 76019817-272-2142 (voice) • 817-272-3006 (fax)
Related LinksAbout the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
